Finding Aid for William Albright Papers 1962-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Scores
  - Organ Music
    - Finney, Ross Lee
      - Bleheris: a monody from the Hamlet of A. MacLeish, 1937 (Box 24)
      - Five Fantasies for Organ circa 1970 (Box 24)
        (signed by composer and annotated)
      - Quintet for Piano and Strings, 1953 (Box 24)
      - Seventh Quartet, 1955 and Eighth Quartet, 1960 (Box 24)
      - Third Sonata in A for Violin and Piano, 1957 (Box 24)
      - "The Music of Ross Lee Finney," by Paul Cooper, in The Musical Quarterly, January, 1967 (Box 24)
    - Foley, David F.
      - Pantocrator: a fantasy based on "Victimae paschali laudes" for pipe organ, undated (Box 48)
    - Fortner, Jack
      - Found Objects, 1985 (Box 24)
    - Franck, Cesar
      - Prelude Fugue et Variation, 1946 (Box 24)
      - Three Chorales for Organ, 1948 (Box 24)
    - Freudenthaler, Erland M.
      - Wie unbegreiflich bist Du, o Gott, Praludium fur Orgel solo, 1988 (Box 24)
    - Gershwin, George
      - Do do do (transcribed by W.A.), undated (Box 24)
    - Grainger, Percy Aldridge
      - The Immovable Do, 1939 (Box 24)
    - Harris, Donald
      - Meditations, 1984 (Box 24)
    - Harris, Tom Robin
      - Dance of the Calliopes for Organ, 1989 (Box 24)
    - Hershey, Sharon
      - Organbook, undated (Box 48)
    - Hendrie, Gerald
      - Specula Petro for Organ, undated (Box 24)
    - Hill, Jackson
      - Five Zen Fragments, 1979 (Box 24)
    - Hoag, Charles
      - Quantrill's Raid, 1978 (Box 24)
    - Janson, Thomas
      - Celestial Autumn for solo organ, 1973 (Box 24)
      - Aura for organ, 1972 (Box 24)
    - Hodkinson, Sydney
      - Dolmen for organ solo: Megalith I, 1973 (Box 24)
      - Menhir for Organ Solo: Megalith II, 1973 (Box 24)
      - Organasm: a Scenario for organ solo and assistants, 1968 (Box 24)
        (dedicated to W.A.)
      - Papillons Book 3, 1984 (Box 24)
      - Sinfonia Fantastica, undated
        - correspondence undated (Box 24)
      - Talayot for Two Organs: Megalith III, 1973 (Box 24)
    - Ives, Charles
      - Variations on "America" for Organ (1891) and Adeste Fidelis in an Organ Prelude (1897) (Box 25)
    - Joachim, Otto
      - Tribute to St. Romanus, 1980 (Box 25)
    - Johnson, Tom
      - Melodie de Six Notes pour orgue, 1982 (Box 25)
    - Klausmeyer, Peter
      - The Hound of Morrisville, 1977 (Box 48)
      - Seven Studies for a Summer Evening for tracker-action organ, 1978 (Box 48)
    - Kuhnau, Johann
      - Biblical Sonata I, 1700 (Box 25)
    - Levines, Thomas Allen
      - Ave, Generosa: Seven Studies on Themes by Bingen for Organ, 1986 (Box 48)
      - Eidolons: Three Preludes and Fugues for Organ, 1982 (Box 48)
      - Luminis: Three Variations on a Theme by Crumb (Meditations III) for organ, 1986 (Box 48)
    - Ligeti, Gyorgy
      - Volumina fur orgel, 1962 (Box 48)
    - Linke, Norbert
      - Ritual for organ, 1969 (Box 25)
    - Locklair, Dan
      - A Suionata of Inventions for organ, 1978 (Box 25)
    - Lynch, J.H
      - Lament for Frank Allbright, undated (Box 25)
    - Messiaen, Olivier
      - Le Banquet Celeste, 1926 (Box 25)
      - Livre d'Orgue: Sept Pieces pour Orgue circa 1958 (Box 25)
      - La Nativite du Seigneur: Neuf Meditations pour Orgue, circa 1936 (Box 25)
    - Morris, Robert
      - Curtain, 1976 (Box 57)
        (dedicated to W.A. and annotated)
    - Morris, Stephen
      - Z-10 for organ, 1984 (Box 57)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
      - Fantaisie en fa Mineur 1791 (Box 25)
    - Nichifor, Serban
      - Schite Pentru o Barcarola Esquisses pour une Barcarole (In cautarea melodiei pierdute), 1978 (Box 25)
    - Nordensten, Frank Tveor
      - And Here You Are, 1978 (Box 48)
      - Phase 16 for organ, 1981 (Box 48)
      - 1re Piece pour orgue, 1971 (Box 48)
    - Pape, Gerard
      - Cerberus: concerto for organ and tape, 1987 (Box 25)
        (commissioned by and dedicated to W.A.)
    - Parris, Robert
      - Variations for Organ 1978 (Box 25)
    - Passmore, David
      - Prelude for Organ, 1980 (Box 25)
    - Peck, Russell
      - Automobile for percussion, bass, flute and soprano, 1965 (Box 25)
      - In the Garden, undated (Box 25)
    - Pellegrini, Ernesto
      - Fantasia per Organo, 1971 (Box 25)
    - Persichetti, Vincent
      - Parable for Organ,ca., 1972 (Box 25)
    - Phan, P.Q.
      - Banana Trumpet Games, 1993
        - correspondence 1994 (Box 25)
      - Hocus-Pocus, 1993 (Box 25)
    - Pirchner, Werner
      - Kleine Messe Um "C" fur den Lieben Gott 1982 (Box 25)
    - Primosch, James
      - Meditations on the Mysteries of the Rosary, 1978 (Box 25)
    - Read, Gardner
      - And There Appeared unto Them Tongues as of Fire, circa 1978 (Box 25)
    - Reale, Paul
      - Fantasie for Organ, 1970 (Box 25)
    - Retzel, Frank
      - Dispersion for pipe organ, 1977 (Box 48)
    - Ross, Williams James
      - Partite on a Methodist Hymn: O for a Thousand Tongues to Sing, Azmon, 1986 (Box 25)
      - A Solemn Magnificat: Magnificat Tertii Toni, Opus 27: Six Versets for Organ, 1988 (Box 48)
      - Sun Traces: Organ Trio, 1971 (Box 25)
      - These Forty Days: Fifteen Hymn Preludes for Lent, 1987 (Box 25)
      - Three Dances of Man for organ, percussion, and six dancers, 1981 (Box 25)
      - Vietnam Memorial for Organ, 1971 (Box 25)
      - The Way From Earth, circa 1975 (Box 25)
    - Rouse, Christopher
      - Liber Daemonum for Large Organ, 1981 (Box 25)
    - Rouse, Steve
      - Crosswinds for William Albright, Carl St. Clair, and the University of Michigan Contemporary Directions Ensemble, undated (Box 26)
        (organ part annotated)
    - Sahl, Michael
      - Theatre Organ Piece, 1965 (Box 26)
      - Fantasy Music for Organ, 1967 (Box 26)
    - Schober, Brian
      - Toccatas and Fantasias for organ, 1987 (Box 26)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold
      - Variations on a Recitative, circa 1947 (Box 26)
    - Schilling, Hans Ludwig
      - Von Himmel hoch..., 1962 (Box 26)
    - Schwantner, Joseph
      - In Aeternum II, 1972 (Box 48)
    - Shere, Charles
      - Handler of Gravity (Suppress the Center), 1971 (Box 26)
    - Somers, Steven H
      - Variations for Organ, 1985 (Box 26)
    - Sowerby, Leo
      - Toccata, circa 1941 (Box 26)
    - Stiller, Andrew
      - Three Simple Settings, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Stover, Harold
      - Ezekiel, 1974 (Box 26)
      - Nocturnes Book III, 1979 (Box 26)
      - Nocturnes Book IV, 1980 (Box 26)
      - Scotland Variations for organ, 1982 (Box 26)
      - Three Nocturnes, 1972 (Box 26)
    - Strayhorn, Billy
      - Lotus (Lotus Blossom), 1968 (Box 26)
        (arrangement by Alec Wyton1986 includes note from arranger) (annotated)
    - Suda, Peeter
      - Scherzino (1916), Gigue a la Bach (1919), and Pastorale (1920) (Box 26)
    - Thome, Janell
      - The Canonical Hours for organ 1988 (Box 26)
    - Toensing, Richard
      - Concerto for Piano and Winds, 1979 (Box 57)
        (includes note from composer; annotated)
      - Doxologies II for organ, 1968 (Box 48)
      - Homage to David Smith for Organ, 1980 (Box 26)
      - Processions for Baroque Organ, 1978 (Box 26)
      - Sounds and Changes II for Organ, 1966 (Box 26)
      - Sounds and Changes IV for Organ and Percussion, 1978 (Box 48)
    - Vierne, Louis
      - Pieces de Fantaisie pour Grand Orgue, circa 1927 (Box 26)
    - Vignelaure
      - Prelude et Fugue pour orgue, undated (Box 26)
    - Waller, Thomas "Fats"
      - St. Louis Blues: A "Hot" Transcription for Organ, 1928 (Box 26)
    - Wiley, Frank
      - Fantasia Super Bach for organ, 1973 (Box 26)
    - Wilson, Olly
      - Expansions, 1979 (Box 26)
    - Winsor, Phil
      - Orgel for pipe organ, 1968 (Box 26)
    - Hakim, Naji
      - The Embrace of Fire (Three Movements for Organ), undated (Box 26)
      - Nocturne, undated (Box 26)
  - Various Composers
    - Adams, Richard (student)
      - Synergies, 1993 (Box 27)
      - Movements for Orchestra, 1998 (Box 27)
        (University of Michigan dissertation, W.A. chair)
    - Aikman, James (student)
      - Piano Quintet, 1997 (Box 27)
    - Aitken, Hugh
      (high school composition teacher)
      - Fifteen Short Pieces: piano and string orchestra, 1960 (Box 27)
      - Montages: partita for solo bassoon, 1962 (Box 27)
      - Piano Fantasy 1966 (Box 27)
      - Quintet: oboe, string quartet, 1957 (Box 27)
      - Seven Piano Pieces, 1957 (Box 27)
    - Albert, Stephen
      - Memorial brochure 1993 (Box 27)
    - Alexandra, Liana
      - Concerto for flute, viola and chamber orchestra, 1980 (Box 27)
    - Alkan, Vin (friend)
      - Bombardo-Carillon for Pedal Solo, 4 feet undated (Box 27)
    - Allen, Craig
      - Jerusalem Diary for Chamber Orchestra and Jazz Complement, undated (Box 27)
      - New Traditions for Mezzo and Cello 1998 (Box 27)
    - Alston, Lettie Beckon
      - Conquest of Jericho, 1990 (Box 27)
      - Portrait in Black, 1992 (Box 27)
    - Anderson, Dennis (student)
      - Shadow Fantasy for harp and percussion, 1977 (Box 48)
    - Angell, Michael (student)
      - Elegy for Anne, 1993 (Box 48)
      - Sonata for Cello and Tape, 1997 (Box 27)
      - Symphony, 1993 (Box 48)
    - Armstrong, John (student)
      - Sequence for Orchestra and Guitar, 1982 (Box 27)
    - Asia, Daniel
      - Statement from the composer undated (Box 27)
      - Gateways for Orchestra, 1993 (Box 27)
      - Piano Concerto, 1994 (Box 27)
      - Why (?) Jacob for Solo Piano, 1995 (Box 27)
    - Asplin, David B. (student)
      - Collisions in Silence: To the victims of the Persian Gulf War, 1992 (Box 27)
      - For the Healing of the Nations: A Cantata for Peace, SSATB a cappella, 1996 (Box 27)
      - Jubilate Deo: SATB divisi, a cappella, 1997 (Box 27)
      - Of Light and Shadow for orchestra, 1994 (Box 57)
        (University of Michigan dissertation, W.A. chair; includes abstract and correspondence)
    - Aubertin, Valery
      - Le Livre Ouvert op.6 pour orgue, 1994 (Box 27)
      - Situations, 1988-1996 (Box 27)
      - ...Et le Soleil se Dechirait (22 fragments d'une etoile, op.7) pour orchestre, 1995 (Box 48)
    - Banfield, William C. (student)
      - Dream Realized/Nightmare Resolved: Symphony No.2, 1992 (Box 49)
        (University of Michigan dissertation, W.A. chair; includes abstract)
    - Barwin, Gary
      - Ives' Blues for jazz orchestra, 1987 (Box 57)
      - Music for Esperanto Children: Brian Boru, 1986 (Box 57)
      - Westron Winde (text anonymous Middle English), 1986 (Box 57)
    - Bass, Jeffery
      - A Windless Day for Mixed Chorus and Piano, circa 1995 (Box 27)
    - Bassett, Leslie
      (University of Michigan professor)
      - Concerto for Orchestra, circa 1992 (Box 28)
      - Configurations: Five Piano Pieces, 1987 (Box 28)
      - Echoes from an Invisible World: Three Movements for Orchestra, 1975 (Box 28)
      - Elaborations: Piano Solo, copyright, 1973 (Box 28)
      - Five Pieces for String Quartet, 1957 (Box 28)
      - Liturgies for organ, 1980 (Box 28)
      - Moon Canticle for Large Mixed Chorus, A Cappella, with Cello Obbligato, 1969 (Box 28)
    - Bates, David S.
      (friend, students together)
      - Piano Sonata, 1966 (Box 28)
      - Suena for viola and piano, undated (Box 28)
      - Till Then for piano, undated (Box 28)
    - Beavers, Kevin (student)
      - Sergeloop, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Sonata for violin and piano, 1996 (Box 28)
      - 3 for 3 1995 (Box 28)
    - Beckwith, John
      - Upper Canadian Hymn Preludes for solo organ, with optional concrete-sound interludes, 1977 (Box 28)
    - Beeferman, Gordon (student)
      - La Aurora (The Dawn in New York) from Symphony #1 1997 (Box 49)
    - Bekaert, Jacques
      - The Day After..., 1969 (Box 28)
      - Good Morning, Mister Chopin, 1969 (Box 28)
      - Quiet Space: on a painting by Mark Rothko, four channels tape and any number of instruments, singers, dancers, 1971 (Box 28)
      - Summer Music #1 to 26, 1970 (Box 28)
      - Untitled undated (Box 28)
    - Ben-Amots, Ofer
      - Avis Urbanus for Amplified Flute, 1990 (Box 57)
      - Psalm 23 for Voice, Clarinet and Percussion, 1990 (Box 57)
    - Benjamin, William (student)
      - Etude for Piano, 1974 (Box 28)
      - Two Pieces for String Trio, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Berio, Luciano
      - Cinque Variazioni: per pianoforte, 1953 (Box 28)
      - Circles: for female voice, harp, 2 percussion players 1960 (Box 28)
        (text by e.e. cummings) (includes W.A.'s notes on the composer)
    - Bermel, Derek (student)
      - Carnaval Noir 1997 (Box 28)
      - Lukwanda Sings: for large orchestra, 1990 (Box 28)
      - Quartet #1 for strings 1992 (Box 49)
      - Three Songs on Poems by Wendy Walters: for baritone voice and piano, 1993 (Box 28)
      - Turning: for piano, 1995 (Box 28)
      - Two Songs from Nandom 1993 (Box 28)
        (dedicated to and edited by W.A.; annotated)
      - Voices: concerto for clarinet and orchestra, 1997 (Box 49)
        (University of Michigan dissertation, co-chairs W.A. and William Bolcom; includes abstract)
    - Bhushan, Nag
      - String Quartet, 1997 (Box 28)
    - Bielawa, Bruce (friend)
      - Beat Clinic for Big Band, 1991 (Box 49)
    - Bielawa, Herbert
      - Blackbirds: Prelude and Fugue on a Theme by Olivier Messiaen for organ, 1979 (Box 28)
      - Feedback for Pipe Organ and Orchestra 1996 (Box 28)
        (includes letter from composer)
      - Monophonies for organ, 1979 (Box 28)
    - Biggs, Hayes
      - Child of the Ravenhair, 1988 (Box 49)
      - E.M. Am Flugel: Poem-Etude for Piano Solo, 1992 (Box 29)
      - God Hath Sent Me to Sea for Pearls, 1992 (Box 29)
      - Northeast Reservation Lines for Soprano and Piano, 1984 (Box 29)
      - O magnum mysterium, 1990 (Box 29)
      - Sephestia's Song to Her Child, 1991 (Box 29)
    - Blake, Braxton
      - Etudes: Alto Saxophone and Marimba, 1997 (Box 29)
      - Sonata for Alto Saxophone and Piano, 1992 (Box 29)
      - Suite for Cello, 1991 (Box 29)
      - Three Pieces for Piano, 1989 (Box 29)
    - Blank, Allan
      - Diversions for Solo Clarinet, 1972 (Box 29)
      - Two Holy Sonnets by John Donne, 1977 (Box 49)
    - Boelter, Karl (student)
      - No Longer of That World: A semi-theatrical concert work for five-piece chamber ensemble 1988 (Box 29)
      - Souls: A song cycle for Soprano and Tenor with Piano, 1996 (Box 29)
      - World for the Beholder: A Cantata for chorus and orchestra with mezzo-soprano and baritone soloists, 1981 (Box 29)
    - Boesmans, Philippe
      - Upon La Mi, 1972 (Box 29)
      - Sur Mi pour deux pianos, orgue electrique & percussion, 1974 (Box 29)
    - Bolcom, William (friend)
      - All Right, Albright! Grand Super Fantasy Rag! (or California Porcupine), 1968 (Box 29)
      - Black Host, 1967 (Box 29)
        (dedicated to W.A., annotated)
      - The Brooklyn Dodge, 1972 (Box 29)
      - Four Lost Rags, 1968-1970 (Box 29)
      - The Garden of Eden, 1969 (Box 29)
      - Ghost Rags, 1971 (Box 29)
      - The Graceful Ghost, 1970 (Box 29)
      - Hydraulis for Organ 1971 (Box 29)
        (edited by W.A., annotated)
      - Knight Hubert 1971 (Box 29)
      - Last Rag (in The Ragtime Current: Piano Solos by a Mainstream of Today's Ragtime Composers, E.B. Marks, 1976) (Box 29)
      - Morning and Evening Poems, 1966 (Box 29)
      - Mysteries for organ, 1976 (Box 29)
      - Piano Concerto, undated (Box 29)
      - Praeludium for vibraphone and organ, 1969 (Box 29)
      - Satires for Madrigal Group, 1972 (Box 29)
      - Seabiscuits Rag, 1967 (Box 29)
      - Session 3 for clarinet, violin, violoncello, piano, percussion, 1967 (Box 29)
      - Tabby Cat Walk, 1968 (Box 29)
      - Three Classical Rags, 1967 (Box 29)
      - Three Popular Rags, 1968 (Box 29)
      - Trio for Clarinet, Violin and Piano (Box 29)
        (dedicated to W.A., includes note from composer)
      - Two Games, 1971 (Box 29)
        (dedicated to W.A.; signed and annotated by composer)
    - Borishansky, Elliot
      - Aunt Nina's Golden Machine for trumpet and 6 actors, copyright, 1976 (Box 29)
      - Three Pieces for Piano Solo, 1967 (Box 29)
    - Boulez, Pierre
      - Pli Selon Pli--Don, Partition copyright, 1967 (Box 49)
    - Boury, Robert (student)
      - Song of the Silver Pine for voice, clarinet, string trio and piano op.26a, 1987 (Box 30)
      - Two Love Songs for voice, flute, clarinet and piano op.28, 1987 (Box 30)
    - Broening, Benjamin (student)
      - In the Wind My Rescue Is: chorus, tenor solo and small orchestra, copyright, 1997 (Box 30)
    - Buchanan, Sara
      - Cuma for five players, undated (Box 30)
    - Buel, Charlie
      - Transformations for pipe organ, 1970 (Box 30)
    - Burke, John
      - Near Rhymes for saxophone quartet, 1984 (Box 30)
    - Buhr, Glenn
      - Beren and Luthien, After the mythical tale by J.R.R. Tolkien: For Orchestra, 1984 (Box 30)
    - Burt, George
      - Boundaries: Movement for Viola and Piano 1994 (Box 30)
    - Bussotti, Sylvano
      - Five Piano Pieces 1959 (Box 30)
        (includes notes by W.A.[?])
    - Cacioppo, Curt
      - Ciclo Metamorfico Sul Nome D'un Maestro: Undici Pezzi per Pianoforte, 1988 (Box 30)
      - Echoes Returning to Song: melodies from a New England powwow transcribed, edited and with commentary, 1988 (Box 30)
      - Pawnee Preludes for piano, 1981 (Box 30)
      - Klavierstuck, 1977 (Box 30)
      - Sonata Trasfigurata, 1986 (Box 30)
      - Snake Dance Trio (Coyohim-Katcina) for flute, cello and piano, copyright, 1985 (Box 49)
      - To a Child Dancing in the Wind: orchestral poem with soprano (by W.B. Yeats), 1982 (Box 49)
    - Cacioppo, George (friend)
      - Advance of the Fungi, 1964/66 (Box 30)
      - Bestiary 1: Eingang for Soprano and Percussion, copyright, 1976 (Box 30)
      - Cassiopeia copyright, 1962 (Box 57)
      - Holy Ghost Vacuum, or America Faints, 1966 (Box 30)
      - MOD 3, undated (Box 30)
      - Moves upon Silence for percussion and voice, undated (Box 30)
      - Time on Time in Miracles copyright, 1969 (Box 30)
    - Cage, John
      - Dream for organ, 1948 (Box 30)
    - Cardew, Cornelius
      - Thalmann Variations, 1992-1993, 1974 (Box 30)
      - "Wiggly Lines and Wobbly Music" undated (Box 30)
        (article in unidentified publication)
    - Carpenter, Kurt
      - Sheherazade Sings..., 1984 (Box 30)
    - Cassidy, Brandon
      - Four works (Box 57)
    - Chambers, Evan (student)
      - Bill's Birthday Reel, written for Bill Albright's 50th, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Come Down Heavy! For Alto Saxophone, Violin, and Piano, 1994 (Box 31)
      - Garden of Stones for orchestra, 1989 (Box 49)
      - Polka Nation for symphony band, 1996 (Box 31)
      - String Quartet: Three Memories, 1992 (Box 31)
      - Three Islands 1993 (Box 49)
      - Three Islands for orchestra, 1993 (Box 31)
      - The Trouble with the Wind for saxophone quartet, 1990 (Box 31)
    - Chang, Dorothy (student)
      - Sunan Dances for orchestra, copyright, 1995 (Box 31)
    - Chen, Huey-Ling
      - Enquiry: Duet for Cello and Piano, 1992 (Box 31)
      - First String Quartet, 1990 (Box 31)
      - Large chamber music for woodwinds, strings, harp, piano and percussions, undated (Box 49)
      - Music for piccolo, flute, alto flute, bass flute and piano, 1990 (Box 31)
      - Piano Trio for Violin, Cello and Piano, 1991 (Box 31)
      - Two Vocal Pieces for Soprano, 1993 (Box 31)
    - Child, Peter
      - Tableaux II, 1992 (Box 31)
    - Childs, Barney
      - Barnard I, 1968 (Box 31)
      - Organ Piece for William Albright, 1968 (Box 31)
    - Chuck, Gavin P
      - Outcome for string quartet, 1993 (Box 57)
      - Point of Departure for small orchestra, 1992 (Box 57)
    - Cionek, Edmund
      - In Memoriam Casey Stengel for piano, undated (Box 31)
    - Clement, Sheree
      - Five Nocturnes, 1976 (Box 31)
      - Flex, 1974 (Box 31)
    - Contreras, Jesus Manuel
      - What's the Use of a Title for soprano and orchestra, 1996 (Box 49)
    - Cowgill, Koren
      - The Lovesong of J. Alfred Prufrock for voice and piano (by T.S. Eliot), 1989 (Box 31)
      - Octet for oboe/english horn, bassoon/contrabassoon, horn, trumpet, bass trombone, piano, violin, and violoncello, 1992 (Box 31)
      - Song on a Text of Catullus for medium voice, harp and string quartet, 1991 (Box 31)
      - The Wrathful and the Sullen for orchestra, 1993 (Box 31)
    - Crawford, Lisa (student)
      - Invention, undated (Box 32)
      - Murder Scene #217, undated (Box 32)
      - Piano Concerto #1 (1976) arranged for orchestra, 1991 (Box 32)
      - Rondo for Joyous Mourning: Third Movement from Three Excerpts from Life, undated (Box 32)
      - Sonata Gravita, undated (Box 32)
      - Theme and Variations for piano, undated (Box 32)
      - Untitled for Solo Violin, 1988 (Box 50)
    - Currier, Nathan
      - Chants and Dances for orchestra, 1989 (Box 32)
      - Essor: Five Fantasias for orchestra, undated (Box 32)
      - Ozonedance, 1989 (Box 32)
    - Curtis-Smith, C. (close friend)
      - (Bells) Belle du jour for chamber orchestra, 1974 (Box 32)
      - Ensembles/Solos for two pianos, clarinet, sax, horn, trumpet, vibraphones, guitar, harp, violin, viola and cello, 1977 (Box 32)
      - Fantasy Pieces for Violin and Piano, 1987 (Box 32)
      - Five Sonorous Inventions for Violin and Piano, 1973 (Box 32)
      - For Gatsby, undated (Box 32)
      - The Great American Symphony, 1981 (Box 32)
      - Ordres for piano, 1973 (Box 32)
      - Piano and Wind Sextet, 1991 (Box 32)
      - Second Piano Trio ("The Secret Heart of Sound"), 1993 (Box 50)
      - Suite in Four Movements for harpsichord, 1975 (Box 32)
      - Sundry Dances, 1979/80 (Box 32)
      - Tristana Variations for piano, 1976 (Box 32)
      - Unisonics for alto saxophone and piano, 1976 (Box 32)
    - Dallapiccola, Luigi
      - Quaderno Musicale di Annalibera per Pianoforte 1953 (Box 32)
    - Daugherty, Michael (student)
      - Dead elvis for chamber ensemble, copyright, 1993 (Box 32)
      - Desi for Symphonic Winds, 1991 (Box 32)
      - Lex for violin and orchestra, 1993 (Box 50)
      - Oh Lois!, 1989 (Box 33)
      - Snap, 1987 (Box 33)
    - Davis, Jerome
      - Composition for Alto Saxophone and Piano, 1974 (Box 33)
    - Davis, Sam
      - Three Pieces in Three for Solo Piano, 1997 (Box 33)
    - De Jong, Conrad
      - Song and Light for High Voice and Tuned Percussion/piano (by Irving Feldman), 1975 (Box 33)
    - Desjardins, Jacques A. (student)
      - Decimations for soprano, mixed chorus and chamber orchestra, 1993 (Box 50)
    - Dollarhide, Theodore (student)
      - The Cloud of the Night and the Wind are Alone: Concerto for Viola, Winds, Percussion and Bass, undated (Box 50)
      - Music for the Food King for woodwinds, brass and percussion, undated (Box 33)
    - Donatoni, France
      - For Grilly: Improvvisazione per 7, 1960 (Box 33)
    - Druckman, Jacob
      - Brangle for Orchestra, 1989 (Box 33)
    - Dykstra, Brian
      - False Spring: Concert Rag for Piano Solo, 1976 (Box 33)
      - A Real Fast Rag: Concert Rag, 1976 (Box 33)
    - Dzubay, David
      - Chansons Innocentes (by E.E. Cummings), copyright, 1990 (Box 33)
      - Snake Alley, copyright, 1990 (Box 50)
    - Eberhard, Dennis
      - Janus Music for three orchestras, 1979 (Box 33)
    - Eidschun, Robert
      - Bron-yr-aur Stomp for full chamber ensemble, 1993 (Box 33)
      - Endless Summer...for chamber ensemble, 1995 (Box 33)
    - Eitan, Zohar
      - A Philadelphia Diary: Eighteen Haiku for Piano, 1986 (Box 33)
      - A Tale for piano, with recitation, 1987 (Box 33)
    - Felciano, Richard
      - Five Short Pieces for Piano, 1986 (Box 33)
      - San Francisco Symphony, 1981 (Box 33)
    - Feldman, Morton
      - For Franz Kline, 1962 (Box 33)
    - Ferko, Frank